Guide to the Joseph North and Helen Oken North Family Papers TAM.605
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Photographs, 1935-1972; 0.75 Linear Feet
  - Lydia and Dave Mates Slides: Berlin, undated; 1 folder (Box 14)
  - Lydia and Dave Mates Slides: Kremlin, undated; 1 folder (Box 14)
  - Lydia and Dave Mates Slides: Leningrad, undated; 1 folder (Box 14)
  - Lydia and Dave Mates Slides: Moscow, 1 folder (Box 14)
- Series V: Artifacts, circa 1930s
  This series contains artifacts related the Spanish Civil War including a hat taken off of a Moorish soldier who died in the war, a record of Flamenco music, and Spanish castanets. The series also contains an Odessa sailor's hat and several assorted pins and metals related to various Communist and peace organizations.
  - Hat: From a Tsarist-era Russian Naval Uniform, undated (Box 12)
  - Hat: From a Moroccan Soldier during Spanish Civil War, undated (Box 13)
  - Record of Flamenco Music: Cante Jondo by Orestes Menendez with Carlos Montoya on Guitar (Box 12)
  - Spanish Castanets (Box 14)
  - Pins and Medallions Related to Communist and Peace Organizations, undated; 5 items (Box 14)